





BHARATHKUMARRAJU DASARAJU

PRODUCT DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER - SingTel, SINGAPORE

BIO DETAILS ONLINE CONTACT http://bharathkumaraju.com Singapore DOB: 12-June-1987 t: +65 90829964 Passport: J7879295 in in.linkedin.com/in/dasararaju

e: bhrth.dsra1@gmail.com github.com/bharathkumarraiu

SUMMARY:

Over 8 years IT experience in DevOps and CLOUD in mission critical environments across the Streaming, Aviation, Financial and GPS industries.

Extensive hands-on of DevOps with strong analytical, design and problem solving skills.

Built a fully automated elastic stack based solution for log aggregation and data analytics running on docker containers.

Proven track of highly successful projects development in design, implementation, automation, continuous deployment(CICD) pipelines for real-time and low-latency applications.

TECHNICAL PROFILE:

DevOps AWS Cloud, Ansible, Terraform, Git, Bamboo, Vagrant, Docker, Github, Jira, Jenkins, Gradle, Nginx.

Elastic stack Elasticsearch, Kibana, Functionbeat, Logstash, Filebeat, metricbeat, packetb

Python, Shell Scripting. Programming Oracle, PostgreSQL, MySQL. **RDBMS**

Linux: RedHat, CentOS. Debian, Ubuntu, Coreos, Redhat Atomic OS

Infrastructure Docker, Kubernetes, Virtual Machine, Vagrant, Amazon Web Service, Google Cloud Platform. Certifications AWS Solution Architect, Google cloud professional architect, Terraform certified professional

EXPERIENCE:

SingTel. Automating the infrastructure using pulumi in google cloud with python programming with TDD.

(2021)Deploying the containerized apps in both AWS and GoogleCloud using CICD

NTUC. Dockerized the applications and moved them from GCE VMs to cloud run serverless in Google cloud.

Singapore, Implemented IAC(Infrastructure As a Code) using terraform for googlecloud.

(2020)Implemented CICD Pipeline using Bitbucket pipelines to promote deployments seem lessly.

Automated AWS Cloud deployments and builds using the github actions. **HOOQ TV, Singapore**

Implemented IAC(Infrastructure As a Code) using terraform for AWS cloud were dockerized apps are running. (2019-2020)

Working on openshift container platform to move legacy apps to k8s.

SingaporeAirlines,

Automated Bamboo deployments and builds using the Bamboo specs. Singapore Implemented automated backup solution for complex applications. (2019)

Worked in k8s setup and federated Prometheus monitoring for the k8s cluster and apps.

Delivion GmBH, Essen, Germany (2017-2019)

Automated Complicated WebMethods Stack Provisioning using CICD pipeline. Implemented Centralized log aggregation/Analytics using Elastic

Stack.

Implemented k8s Multi-master setup for containerized solution.

Standard Chartered, Chennai. India

Worked on Immutable automated deployments using Cliqr/Terraform.

Created Development, QA, Stage, Production stacks & maintained them securely using robust VPC design. Automated (2014-2016)

resource cleanup using AWS Lambda as part of cost saving effort.

Implemented application monitoring using DataDog & integrated with AWS environment.

Trimble Navigation, Chennai. India (2012-2014)

Administered DHCP,DNS, LDAP, AD and NFS services on RHEL in Development/Production environments.

EDUCATION:

MCA-Post Graduation

(Jun2007-Jun2010) Information System and Computer Science

UNIX Networking, Java, Information Systems, information security, e-business

BSC- Graduation (Jul2004-May2007)

Mathematics, Physics, Chemistry

Courses: Applied Mathematics, Organic Chemistry, Atomic Physics.

LANGUAGES:

Fluent in English, Telugu, Tamil, Hindi, German.

INTERESTS:

Technology trends and news, travelling, football, movies.